(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
重大告知あり
Big announcement included
よいこらせ
Heave-ho
どっこいしょ
パニョ、パニョ、パニョ、パニョ
Panyo, panyo, panyo, panyo
危険
DANGER
うわぁ！
Whoa!
おっとっとっとっと…
Whoops-a-daisy...
お客様！
Excuse me, miss!
席にお戻りください！
Please return to your seat!
みんな待ってるから行かないと！
Everyone's waiting, so I have to go!
危ないですよ！
It's dangerous!
え？
Eh?
よいしょー！
Heave-ho!
ちょ、ちょっと！
Wa- Wait!
うわああああああ！
Waaaaaaaaaaah!
音乃瀬奏 生誕祭2025
Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025
音乃瀬奏でーす！
I'm Otonose Kanade!
本番！
Showtime!
奏がやってきたー！
Kanade is here!
お前ら！盛り上がってく準備は
Everyone! Are you ready
できてるよなー！
to get hyped?!
君の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your voice
さあ 冒険してみない？
Come on, won't you go on an adventure?
楽しいこと始めよう
Let's start something fun
遊びたい 絶対 タイ！タイ！タイ！
I want to play, absolutely! Want to! Want to! Want to!
I wanna Joy to joy to joy to pop na baby
Joy to joy to joy to happy na say yeah!
君の心は そうもっと do do
Your heart is, yeah, more do do
僕の心も そういっそ good good
My heart is, yeah, even more good good
弾けてるんじゃない？ It's joyful
Aren't we bursting? It's joyful
パピプペポバブー
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-ba-buu
弱虫なんじゃじゃない
I'm not a coward
自信ありげにピースサイン
Giving a confident peace sign
君の瞳にキスして
I'll kiss your eyes
笑いたい 絶対 タイ！タイ！タイ！
I want to laugh, absolutely! Want to! Want to! Want to!
I wanna Joy to joy to joy to you, baby
Joy to joy to joy to happy na people
君の心も そうもっと do do
Your heart too, yeah, more do do
僕の心も そういっそ good good
My heart too, yeah, even more good good
弾けてるんじゃない？ It's joyful
Aren't we bursting? It's joyful
パピプペポバブー
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-ba-buu
I wanna Joy to joy to joy to pop na baby
Joy to joy to joy to happy na people
ドキドキしちゃうの なんでだろう
I wonder why my heart is pounding
ソワソワしちゃうの なんでだろう
I wonder why I'm so restless
この指に止まるのは どんな運命なんだ
What kind of fate will land on this finger?
全部したいな
I want to do it all
いつだって終わっちゃう
It always comes to an end
Everybody いつか終わっちゃう
Everybody, it'll end someday
いついつもこの時を
Always, always, this moment
最終形はきっと修正なして行こう
The final form needs no correction, let's go
Do, we do, we do, we dat do do
パピプペポバブー 遊びたい 絶対 タイ！タイ！タイ！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-ba-buu, I want to play, absolutely! Want to! Want to! Want to!
I wanna Joy to joy to joy to you, baby
Joy to joy to joy to happy na people
Joy to joy to joy to happy na say yeah!
君の心は そうもっと do do
Your heart is, yeah, more do do
僕の心も そういっそ good good
My heart is, yeah, even more good good
弾けてるんじゃない？ It's joyful
Aren't we bursting? It's joyful
パピプペポバブー
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-ba-buu
Joy!
あれ？
Huh?
うぉっ？
Whoa?
降ろせやー！
Put me down!
降ろしてー！
え？
Eh?
ちゃんと降ろせやー！
I said put me down!
なあああああ！
Noooooooo!
はい！ということで始まりました！
Yes! And so it begins!
音乃瀬奏 生誕祭
Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival
2025！イエーイ！
2025! Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いや、もう大変だったんだよ。飛行機に乗ってここまで来るのにさ。
I mean, it was so tough. Coming all the way here on a plane.
うう、疲れた、もう疲れた。
Ugh, I'm tired, I'm already tired.
ちょっと待って。一応ハーネス取ってくるからみんな待っててね。
Wait a second. I'm going to take off this harness, so everyone wait.
えい、見ないで、えい。
Hey, don't look, hey.
はーい！なんと、なんと！
Hi! And guess what, guess what!
えー、こちら音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025、
Um, this is Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025,
ハッシュタグは…
and the hashtag is...
同じです！
It's the same!
あ、ここに書いてある。
Ah, it's written here.
ここに書いてある通り、
Just as it's written here,
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025でいっぱいポストしてください！
please post a lot using #OtonoseKanadeBirthdayFestival2025!
お願いします！
Please!
そして今回は3Dになって初めてのお誕生日なので、
And since this is my first birthday in 3D,
いろんな音乃瀬奏をみんなに見てもらえたらなと思っています！
I hope you all get to see many different sides of Otonose Kanade!
そして最後には重大告知あり！
And at the end, there's a big announcement!
よかったら最後まで見てください！
Please watch until the end if you'd like!
なんだなんだ、なんだなんだ！？
What's this, what's this!?
すごいコメントがもうすごい速度！
The comments are coming in at an incredible speed!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そしてゲストパートは一部収録です。
And the guest parts are partially pre-recorded.
生で歌ったりえーダンスしたりもするので
I'll also be singing and dancing live,
よかったら見守ってください。
so please watch over me.
すごい草がいっぱいある！ありがとう！
So much 'grass' (lol)! Thank you!
奏ちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！！
Kanade-chan, happy birthday!!
誰！？
Who!?
全然見てない。誰だったかな？忘れちゃった。
I wasn't looking at all. Who was it? I forgot.
ReGLOSSだよ！
It's ReGLOSS!
え、来てくれたの！？
Eh, you guys came!?
もちろん！
Of course!
ありがとうよ！
Thank you!
ちょっと首が首が痛い痛い痛い痛い。
Ow, my neck, my neck hurts, hurts, hurts.
すぐあっち行くから待っててね！
I'll be right over there, so wait for me!
降りてきてくれるんだ！ありがとう！
You're coming down! Thanks!
やば、うちらも先にここ占拠しちゃってるじゃん。いいのかな？
Whoops, we've already occupied this place. Is that okay?
これ占拠なの？これ占拠してるの三人で？
Is this an occupation? The three of us are occupying it?
もう今ジャックしたで。
We've hijacked it now.
おら！
Take that!
シャッチョ、シャッチョ、シャッチョ…
President, President, President...
そうそう、準備できたんじゃない？
Right, right, aren't you ready now?
あ、できた！
Ah, it's done!
もしかして歌うのか？
Are you going to sing by any chance?
え、歌うし踊るよ！
Eh, I'm going to sing and dance!
歌うの？
Singing?
そうだよ！
That's right!
来るか？来るか？
Is it coming? Is it coming?
行くぜ！何が来るんだ？
Here we go! What's coming?
群青讃歌 作詞・作曲 Eve
Gunjo Sanka / Lyrics & Composition by Eve
繋がっていたいって信じられる言葉だって
Even the words I believe in when I want to be connected
もう昨日の僕らにおさらば
Have already said goodbye to who we were yesterday
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
A distant lightning that spent the blue spring
そっと泣いて まだ夜を明けたら
Gently weeping, if the night has still dawned
きっとどんなに楽になれていただろうな
Surely, how much easier it would have been
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
The sliver of hope that shook this heart
無いものねだりは やめた
I've stopped wishing for what I don't have
未完成人間 素晴らしい世界だけが
Incomplete humans, only this wonderful world...
答えを握っている
...holds the answer
諦めてしまうほどに この先たくさんの
So much so that I'm about to give up, ahead of me many...
後悔が君を待ってるけどもうない
...regrets are waiting for you, but they're no longer here
迷いはしないよ この傷も愛おしく思えてしまうほど
I won't hesitate, to the point where even these wounds seem precious
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
They'll overlap, it's fine to be awkward as you are
走れ
Run
その歩幅で
At your own pace
走れ
Run
この声 轟かせてくれ
Let this voice ring out
鳥が飛ぶ
A bird flies
同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace me just as much
静かに今を繋ぐ
Quietly connecting the present
未来 照らして
Illuminate the future
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, whose faces and names are unknown
たった一つの塔を鳴らす
Ring out a single tower
いたずらみたいな
Like a prank,
奇跡のような切な
a miracle-like moment
あっという間に流れる時が
In the blink of an eye, the flowing time
ありのままであり続ける
Continues to be as it is
怖さが
The fear,
失った時間は 取り戻せないけれど
the time lost, though it cannot be taken back
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ
If you're only looking back at the past
泣いたっていいんだ
It's okay to cry
悔しさと痛みだけが
Only the frustration and pain
君を肯定するから
Will affirm who you are
大人になったら 忘れてしまうの
When we grow up, will we forget?
君との約束をした場所は
The place where I made a promise with you
もうない
is no longer there
覚えていたいよ
I want to remember it
思い出も愛おしく思えてしまう
Even the memories seem precious
重なってしまうよ
They stack on top of each other.
不格好なままでいいから
It's fine even if it's unpolished.
その声は どこまでも遠回り 響いて
That voice echoes, wandering endlessly.
確かな理由を抱いて ここまで来たんだ
Embracing a certain reason, I've come this far.
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
The journey hasn't ended yet.
いつか想いは形になって
Someday, these thoughts will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる朝
On this morning dyed in pure white,
忘れないように
So that I won't forget...
だから
That's why...
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many things ahead that I'd almost give up,
もう迷わない、迷いはしないよ
I won't be lost, I won't get lost anymore.
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Irreplaceable things overflow,
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is in your hands.
離さないで、物語は一歩先へ
Don't let go, the story is one step ahead.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの 後悔が君を待ってるけど
There's so much regret waiting ahead that you might give up, but...
もう迷わない、迷いはしないよ
I won't be lost, I won't get lost anymore.
この傷も愛しく思えてしまうほど
To the point where even these scars feel precious,
重なってしまうよ
They keep piling up.
不格好なままでいいから
It's fine to stay unpolished.
走れ その歩幅で
Run at your own pace!
走れ 声を響かせてくれ
Run! Let your voice ring out!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
刻んだ今を 紡ぐ未来 足して
Adding this carved moment to the future we weave.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
改めて、おめでとう！
Once again, congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
待って、そういえば自己紹介してなくね？
Wait, come to think of it, haven't we introduced ourselves?
あー、確かに。
Oh, you're right.
誰ですか？
Who are you guys?
可愛いポジティブジーニアス、火威青の女、一条莉々華です！
I'm the cute positive genius and Ao Hiodoshi's girl, Ririka Ichijou!
火威青の女！？
Ao Hiodoshi's girl!?
へっぽこ番長、轟はじめ、えー、火威青のお姉ちゃんよ！
I'm the clumsy delinquent leader, Hajime Todoroki, and Ao's big sister!
お姉ちゃんじゃねーよ！火威青なんだわ！
I'm not your big sister! I'm Ao Hiodoshi!
ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございます。えー、音乃瀬奏の...コーチ？
I'm Raden Juufuutei from ReGLOSS. And I'm Kanade Otonose's... coach?
コーチ！？何を教えたの！？
Coach!? What did you teach her!?
教わった記憶ないんですけど。見なよ、こっちがコーチな。
I don't remember being taught anything. Look, I'm the coach here.
逆な、それ。
It's the other way around.
ReGLOSSのみんな、来てくれてありがとうー！
Everyone from ReGLOSS, thank you so much for coming!
この曲歌いたかったんだー。
I've really wanted to sing this song.
嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
めっちゃいい曲。
It's such a great song.
ね、最高だった。
Right? It was awesome.
次はゲストパートなんだけど、一緒にコールお願いしてもいいかな？
The next part is the guest part. Can I ask you guys to join the call?
もちろーん！
Of course!
じゃあ行くよ、せーの、どうぞー！
Alright, here we go! One, two, go!
ねえ考えなくていいよ
Hey, you don't have to think about it.
口先じゃわかりあえないの
We can't understand each other with just words.
この音に今は乗ろうよ
Let's just go with the music for now.
忘れないでいたいよ
I want to keep this in my memory.
身体は無彩色レイドバック
Our bodies are colorless and laid back.
ただうねる雨音でグルーヴ
Just grooving to the surging sound of rain.
ずっと二人で暮らそうよ
Let's live together forever,
この夜の隅っこで
in this little corner of the night.
ねえ大概僕らでいいよ
Hey, mostly we're fine as we are.
誘ったのは君じゃないの
It wasn't you who invited me.
理屈だけじゃつまらないわ
Just logic is boring.
まだ時間が欲しいの
I still want more time.
練り歩く景色をシンクバック
Thinking back on the scenery we walked through.
踏み鳴らす足音でグルーヴ
Grooving to the sound of our footsteps.
まるで僕らはブレーメン
It's like we're the Bremen Town Musicians.
たった二人だけの街
In a town of just the two of us.
さあ、息を吸って
Come on, take a breath,
吐いて、吐いて
exhale, exhale.
あ、正々歌ってようぜ
Ah, let's keep singing fair and square.
笑う門には福来るとか
They say fortune comes to those who smile.
愛の歌 奪ってんのさ
We're snatching away the songs of love.
あ、正々楽してこうぜ
Ah, let's just take it easy.
死ぬほどのことはこの世にないぜ
There's nothing in this world worth dying for.
明日は何しようか
What should we do tomorrow?
暇なら笑い合おうぜ
If we're free, let's laugh together.
そのうち分かり合おうぜ
We'll understand each other eventually.
ねぇ考えなくてもいいよ
Hey, you don't have to think about it.
踊り始めた君の細胞
Your cells have started to dance.
この音に今は乗ろうよ
Let's ride this sound for now.
乗れなくてもいいよ
It's okay if you can't ride it.
思い出の景色でバックパック
Backpacking through the scenery of memories.
春風の騒めきでグルーヴ
Grooving with the rustle of the spring breeze.
もっと二人で歌おうよ
Let's sing together more.
暇なら愛をしようよ
If we're free, let's make love.
さぁ 息を吸って
Now, take a breath...
声に出して
...and let it out in your voice.
斉々歌っていようぜ
Let's just keep on singing.
嗤われてるのも仕方ないね
It's okay to be laughed at.
何もかも間違ってんのさ
Everything is wrong anyway.
Ah-ha-ha-ha
斉々楽していこうぜ
Let's just take it easy.
馬鹿なよそ者もラグジュアライズ
Luxurizing even the foolish outsiders.
同じような歌詞だし
The lyrics are all the same anyway.
三番は飛ばしていいよ
You can skip the third verse.
さぁ 息を吸って
Now, take a breath...
早く吐いて
...and exhale quickly.
ねぇ 心を貸して
Hey, lend me your heart...
今日くらいは
...at least for today.
斉々歌っていようぜ
Let's just keep on singing.
違う顔してお前ら皆
All of you, with your different faces...
僕のこと嗤ってんのかい
...are you laughing at me?
斉々楽してこうぜ
Let's just take it easy.
死ぬほど辛いなら逃げ出そうぜ
If it's painful enough to die, let's run away.
数年経てばきっと
In a few years, surely...
一人も覚えてないよ
...no one will remember.
斉々打たれていようぜ
Let's just keep taking the hits.
身体は動く お前もどうだい
My body still moves, how about yours?
哀の歌 歌ってんのさ
I'm singing a song of sorrow.
Ah-ha-ha-ha
斉々楽していこうぜ
Let's just take it easy.
死ぬほどのことはこの世にないぜ
There's nothing in this world worth dying for.
明日は何しようか
What should we do tomorrow?
暇なら笑い合おうぜ
If we're free, let's laugh together.
そのうち分かり合おうぜ
We'll understand each other eventually.
奏 (かなで)
作詞・作曲 大橋卓弥 / 常田真太郎
Kanade
Lyrics & Composition: Takuya Ohashi / Shintaro Tokita
改札の前 つなぐ手と手
In front of the ticket gate, hands joined.
いつものざわめき 新しい風
The usual bustle, a new breeze.
明るく見送るはずだったのに
I was supposed to see you off cheerfully, but...
うまく笑えずに
...I couldn't smile well...
君を見ていた
...and just looked at you.
君が大人になってくその季節が
So that the season when you become an adult...
悲しい歌で溢れないように
...won't be filled with sad songs...
最後に何か君に伝えたくて
...wanting to tell you one last thing at the end...
「さよなら」に代わる言葉を
...for words to replace "goodbye"...
僕は探してた
...I was searching.
君の手を引く
Taking your hand...
…その役目が
...that role of mine
僕の使命だなんて そう思ってた
Was my mission in life, or so I thought
だけど今わかったんだ 僕らならもう
But now I understand; for the two of us,
重ねた日々がほら、導いてくれる
Look, the days we've spent together will guide us.
君が大人になってくその時間が
While the time you spend becoming an adult
降り積もる間に僕も変わってく
Piles up, I will change as well.
たとえばそこにこんな歌があれば
For example, if there were a song like this,
ふたりはいつもどんな時もつながっていける
We could stay connected always, no matter the time.
突然ふいに鳴り響くベルの音
Suddenly, the sound of the departure bell rings out.
焦る僕 解ける手 離れてく君
I panic, our hands part, and you move away.
夢中で呼び止めて 抱きしめたんだ
Frantically, I called out to stop you and held you tight.
君がどこに行ったって僕の声で守るよ
No matter where you go, I will protect you with my voice.
君が僕の前に現れた日から
From the day you first appeared before me,
何もかもが違くみえたんだ
Everything started to look different.
朝も光も涙も、歌う声も
The morning, the light, the tears, and even my singing voice...
君が輝きをくれたんだ
You were the one who gave them their shine.
抑えきれない思いをこの声に乗せて
I'll put these uncontrollable feelings into my voice
遠く君の街へ届けよう
And deliver them to your distant town.
たとえばそれがこんな歌だったら
For example, if it were a song like this,
ぼくらは何処にいたとしてもつながっていける
We could stay connected no matter where we are.
No title / 作詞・作曲: Reol
No title / Lyrics & Music: Reol
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
Have I become the person I always dreamed I'd be?
とうに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
It seems I've come to a point of no return.
自分の足で二段飛ばして
Taking two steps at a time with my own feet,
そうもっと先へ駆けていけるはずだから ran away
I should be able to run further ahead, so I ran away.
深くなる傷を縫い付け
Sewing up the wounds that grow deeper,
繋ぐパス軸に回りだす
I start to spin around the path I connect.
なれた痛み、焦る呼吸とビート
This familiar pain, my frantic breathing and the beat—
気付かないふりしてまた一人
I pretend not to notice and find myself alone again.
何が正当？ないな永劫
What is 'correct'? Nothing lasts forever.
誰が間違った対価払うの
Who will pay the price for the mistakes made?
あんたが嫌いなあいつはきっと
That person you hate is surely
ただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
'incorrect' just because of that one thing.
零点だって提言したって
Even if I'm told I've scored a zero,
全然納得できない理由も
The reason I can't accept it at all is because
最前線はいつだってここだった
The front line has always been right here.
最善策は最初からなかった
There was never a 'best strategy' from the start.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, I'm crumbling and breaking apart.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように
Slowly, slowly, as if being strangled,
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
The 'me' from yesterday is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れあく
Gently, we are pulled further apart.
グラリンリ君に聞こえるのは
Swaying and shaking, what you hear
僕が知らない声になってく
Is becoming a voice I no longer recognize.
幼い頃から 気づいたらそばにいた
Since I was little, you've been by my side
まるで空気のようだ
Just like the air itself
僕は君とぎゅっと手を繋いで
I held your hand tightly
楽しいことも涙も 僕は君に話し聞かせた
The fun times and the tears, I told you everything
僕を笑う人 貶す声 掻き消すように 君は歌った
As if to drown out the laughter and disparaging voices, you sang
この声を君が自身の体温で ずっと温めてくれた
You kept this voice of mine warm with your own heat
使い捨てだって 言ってたって
Even if they say it's disposable
止まらないハイファイ タイトロープ
This unstoppable hi-fi tightrope
一周回るものの たった一瞬だけでも
In a whole cycle, even if it's just for a moment
交わる音 繋ぐ色 次は僕が君に歌うんだ
Intersecting sounds, connecting colors, next I'll sing for you
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, it's collapsing and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, as if tightening a noose, the me from yesterday is killed
ゆるやかに 離れ離れを
Slowly drifting apart
ぷらり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
What you hear as you drift away is becoming a voice I don't know
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, it's collapsing and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, as if tightening a noose, the me from yesterday is killed
ゆるやかに 離れ離れを
Slowly drifting apart
ぷらり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
What you hear as you drift away is becoming a voice I don't know
いつか君に届くかな
Will it reach you someday?
いや そんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
No, that day will surely never come
声も身体もモダン君に 救われた僕の1人
Voice and body, both modernized, I'm one of those who was saved
赤青合わせ彩った
Colored with a mix of red and blue
踊って世界が溢れた
Dancing until the world overflowed
巡り巡り会ったこの音を聴く全てが
Everything that hears this sound we met in a cycle
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, it's collapsing and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, as if tightening a noose, the me from yesterday is killed
ゆるやかに 離れ離れを
Slowly drifting apart
ぷらり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
What you hear as you drift away is becoming a voice I don't know
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, it's collapsing and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, as if tightening a noose, the me from yesterday is killed
ゆるやかに 離れ離れを
Slowly drifting apart
ぷらり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
What you hear as you drift away is becoming a voice I don't know
好き 嫌い 常識 I don’t care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Like it, hate it, common sense, I don’t care - blow it up with a BANG!!!
かかってこい majority あたしに負けはなし
Bring it on, majority, I have no defeat
ここまでって引かれた そのボーダー 誰のルール？
Where did this 'border' come from? Whose rule is it?
あの日の乗り越えた ウィークハート
I overcame the weak heart of that day
強くなった シガ笑い飛ばした
I got stronger, I blew the laughter away
言いたいことは言う やりたくないことはしない
I say what I want to say, I don't do what I don't want to do
悪意気にしない
I don't mind the ill will
同じがの当然だし あたしも変わらない
It's natural to be different, I'm still me
ニューノーマルの時代
The era of the new normal
Everybody say I want to be free
いつもの思いはない それじゃ何も変えられない
No conventional thoughts, then nothing can be changed
Everybody say I want to life more
叶えて自分こそ 生きてるんだって
Make it come true, myself, I am alive
生きてるんだって
I am alive
呼吸から生まれた 空ときから選んできたんだ
Born from a breath, I've chosen since that time
思い出せ あたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am who I am
不可能のことなんて 何一つもない
There's nothing that is impossible
そりゃじゃない 大自分に
That's right, to my great self
好き 嫌い 常識 I don’t care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Like it, hate it, common sense, I don’t care - blow it up with a BANG!!!
震えて鳴らす このリリックかます
Trembling and ringing, firing these lyrics
わからす 挑発 下を向いて舌打ちからの ハッ
Make them understand, provocation, clicking my tongue while looking down, HA!
Excuse me 容赦せず 倍返しクライ パンチライン 聴かせてやるよ
Excuse me, without mercy, double the payback, listen to the punchline
焼き付かせな あたしがついてるから
Make it burn in, because I'm with you
(Everybody say I want to be free)
Yesも Noも言わない それじゃ何も変えられない
I don't say yes or no, I can't change anything with that
(Everybody say I want to live more)
叶えたい自分 肯定
Affirm the self I want to fulfill
生きてるんだ
I'm alive
あたし ねえ 生きてるんだ
Hey, I'm alive
ねえ 生きてるんだ
あたし 歌えや歌え 今を
I sing, I sing now
(声上げて)
(Raise your voice)
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen it since the moment I was born
思い出せ あたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am me
不可解な事など 何一つ無いさじゃないの
There's not a single incomprehensible thing, is there?
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ 迷いも手
I've chosen it since I was born, even the hesitation
あなたはあなただ
You are you
不可解な事など 何一つ無いさじゃないの
There's not a single incomprehensible thing, is there?
あたしは自分だ
I am myself
好き嫌い どっち？ K.I.R.A.I don't care
Love or hate, which one? HATE, I don't care
ぶっ放せ BANG!!!
Fire away, BANG!!!
好き嫌い どっち？ K.I.R.A.I don't care
Love or hate, which one? HATE, I don't care
ぶっ放せ BANG!!!
Fire away, BANG!!!
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
The lonely girl is dreaming forever
届かない夢見て
Seeing dreams that won't reach
騒ぐ頭の中を
Screaming inside her head
掻き回して、掻き回して。
Stirring it up, stirring it up
「問題ない。」と呟いて
Muttering, "No problem."
言葉は失われた？
Were the words lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Another failure, another failure
間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
If it ends in finding mistakes, it spins again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I will roll today as well," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl says, the girl says
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
While playing out the meaning in words!
「もう一回？」「まだですよ、
"One more time?" "Not yet,
まだまだ先は見えないので。
the end is still not in sight.
息を止めるの、今。」
Hold your breath, now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The aftermath of a rolling girl
届かない、向こうの色
The colors beyond that won't reach
重なる声と声を
Mixing voices that overlap
混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
With other voices, mixing them up
「問題ない。」と呟いた
Muttering, "No problem."
言葉は失われた。
The words were lost.
どうなったって良いんだってさ、
She says she doesn't care what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと誘う、坂道。
the slope invites her to even make mistakes.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time
私をどうか転がしてと
Please, somehow, roll me, says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl says, the girl says
無口に意味を重ねながら！
While stacking meaning in silence!
「もう一回？」「もう少し、
"One more time?" "Just a bit more,
もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。
surely something will be visible soon.
息を止めるの、今。」
Hold your breath, now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I will roll today as well," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl says, the girl says
言葉に笑みを重ねながら！
While stacking smiles on her words!
「もう一回！」「もう良いよ。
"One more time!" "That's enough.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ねぇ。」
You must be tired by now, right?"
息をやめるの、今。
Stop breathing, now.
空にある何かを見つめてたら
As I stared at something in the sky
それは星だって君がおしえてくれた
You told me they were stars
まるでそれは僕らみたいに 寄り添ってる
It's as if they're nestling close just like us
二人だって約束した
We vowed that we'd be together
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic to connect to someone
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Tens of times, hundreds of times, we clashed
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
Tens of years, hundreds of years, the light of the past
僕自身も忘れた頃に
By the time I've even forgotten it myself
僕らに届いている
It reaches us
僕ら見つけ合って 語り合って
We found each other, we talked
同じ空 輝くのだって
That we would shine in the same sky
二人だって約束した
We vowed that we'd be together
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic to connect to someone
僕ら肩並べ手取り合って
We stand shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand
進んでく
And move forward
辛い時だって泣かないって
Even in times of pain, we won't cry
誓っただろう
We swore, didn't we?
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, right?
祈りが
The prayer...
記憶を辿るたび蘇るよ
Every time I trace my memories, it comes back to life
君がいつだってそこにいてくれること
That you are always there for me
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
Just like the light of a star
今日も泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Today, too, we cry, laugh, and connect
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Tens of times, hundreds of times, we clashed
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
Tens of years, hundreds of years, the light of the past
僕自身も忘れた頃に
By the time I've even forgotten it myself
僕らを照らしてる
It's shining on us
僕ら見つけ合って 語り合って
We found each other, we talked
同じ空 輝くのだって
That we would shine in the same sky
二人だって約束した
We vowed that we'd be together
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic to connect to someone
どこまで いつまで 生きられるか
How far, and for how long, can we live?
君が不安になるたびに強がるんだ
Every time you get anxious, I pretend to be strong
大丈夫 僕が
It's okay, I'm...
横にいるよ
right by your side
見えないラインを繋ごう
Let's connect the invisible lines
僕ら見つけ合って 語り合って
We found each other, we talked
同じ空 輝くのだって
That we would shine in the same sky
二人だって約束した
We vowed that we'd be together
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic to connect to someone
僕ら肩並べ手取り合って
We stand shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand
進んでく
And move forward
辛い時だって泣かないって
Even in times of pain, we won't cry
誓っただろう
We swore, didn't we?
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, right?
祈りが
The prayer...
空にある何かを
Something in the sky...
見つめてたら
As I stared up at it
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me they were stars
透明よりも綺麗なあの輝きを
That brilliance, clearer than transparency
確かめに行こう
Let's go and see it for ourselves
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began
たまに忘れるほど強い理由
A reason so strong that I sometimes forget it
冷たい雨に濡れる時は
When we get wet in the cold rain
足音数え騒ぎながら行こう
Let's go while counting our footsteps and making noise
太陽の代わりに唄を
A song in place of the sun
君と僕と世界の声で
With your voice, my voice, and the world's voice
いつか君を見つけた時に
When I found you one day
君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
I realized that you had found me too
今目が合えば笑うだけさ
Now, if our eyes meet, we'll just laugh
言葉の外側で
Beyond the realm of words
ゴールはきっとまだだけど もう死ぬまでいたい場所にいる
The goal is surely still far off, but I'm already in the place where I want to stay until I die.
隣で 君のそばで 魂がここだと叫ぶ
By your side, near you, my soul screams that I am here.
泣いたり笑ったりする時 君の命が揺れる時
When we cry and laugh, when your life trembles,
誰より特等席で 僕も同じように 息をしていたい
In the seat of honor more than anyone else, I want to keep breathing just like you.
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
君の一歩は僕より遠い 間違いなく君のすごいところ
Your step is further than mine, without a doubt, that's what's amazing about you.
足跡は僕の方が多い 間違いなく僕のすごいところ
I have more footprints, without a doubt, that's what's amazing about me.
真っ暗闇が怖い時は 怖さを比べ ふざけながら行こう
When the darkness is scary, let's compare our fears and go while fooling around.
太陽がなくたって歩ける 君と照らす世界が見える
I can walk even without the sun, I can see the world lit up with you.
言えないこと 聞かないままで 消えない傷の意味知らないままで
Leaving things unsaid, without asking, without knowing the meaning of the wounds...
でも 目が合えば 笑えるのさ 涙を挟んでも
But if our eyes meet, we can laugh, even through tears.
転んだら 手を貸してもらうよりも 優しい言葉選んでもらうよりも
If I fall, rather than having you lend a hand, or choosing kind words,
隣で信じてほしいんだ どこまでも一緒に行けると
I want you to believe in me by my side, that we can go anywhere together.
ついにたどり着くその時 夢の正体 愛に触れる時
When we finally arrive, when we touch the true nature of dreams and love,
必ず 一番そばで 君の目に映る景色にいたい
I definitely want to be the closest one, in the scenery reflected in your eyes.
あの輝きを 君に会いたから見えた
That radiance, I saw it because I met you.
あの輝きを 確かめに行こう
Let's go check that radiance.
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
どんな最後が待っていようと もう離せない手を繋いだんだよ
No matter what kind of end awaits, I've already held your hand and won't let go.
隣で隣で 君のそばで
By your side, by your side, near you,
魂がここだよと叫ぶ
My soul screams that I'm right here.
そして理由が光る時 僕らを理由が抱きしめる時
And when the reason shines, when the reason embraces us,
誰より近くで 特等席で
Closer than anyone, in the seat of honor,
僕の見た君を君に伝えたい
I want to tell you about the you that I saw.
君がいることを君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all started.
うわ〜！ママ達〜！
Whoa! Mothers!
ママ〜！ ママ〜！
Mama! Mama!
お誕生日おめでとう〜！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！ おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
騒がしいなｗ
So noisy! lol
お前に言われたくないわｗ
I don't want to hear that from you!
確かに、奏ちゃんが一番浮き足立ってるじゃんｗ
True, Kanade-chan is the most excited one!
だ、だって誕生日だから！
B-Because it's my birthday!
そうだねｗ
That's true.
お母さん達、産んでくれてありがとうございます！
Mothers, thank you for giving birth to me!
産んではいないｗ 産んではないｗ
We didn't give birth to you! We didn't!
その誤解やめてｗ
Stop that misunderstanding!
こちらこそだよ〜ｗ
The pleasure is ours!
ママですけども、産んでませんｗ
We are the mothers, but we didn't give birth!
はい、そして今日は何を話すんですか？ ここから
Okay, so what are we talking about now?
そうですね、えーと、これまでのコラボでの感想を...
Well, uh, our impressions of the collaborations so far...
めちゃめちゃ喋るじゃんｗ
She's talking so much!
大丈夫かな？ 言うてｗ
Is she going to be okay? Go on.
じゃあ一番印象深かったの何？ 奏ちゃんが
So, what was the most memorable one for you, Kanade-chan?
でも、言うてママズでやったコラボって、実は1個しかない...
But, to be honest, there's actually only one 'Mamas' collab...
あ〜！ 懐かしい！
Ah! Nostalgic!
懐かしいｗ アンタなぁ〜ｗ
Nostalgic lol. You...
あれ、でもそういえば、なんか赤い髪の毛の人...
Wait, but speaking of which, that person with red hair...
おれ？
Me?
やっぱりあれじゃない？ 『産んだ』とか言う...
Isn't it that one? The one who says 'gave birth'...
あ〜ｗ あの方は...
Ah lol. That person...
あ、でもスケジュール的に... ちょっと都合が合わなくて...
Oh, but in terms of schedule... the timing didn't work out...
次はね、みんなで行きたいよね
Next time, we should all go together.
そうだね
That's right.
コラボとかもしようね
Let's do a collab too.
したいしたい！
I want to, I want to!
やったやったー！イエーイ！
Yay, yay! Hooray!
あの、ゲームコラボ以来ですからね
It's been since the game collab, after all.
そうだねー
That's right.
はい、えーと... 次次次次！次やる！
Okay, um... Next, next, next, next! Let's do the next!
印象印象！印象聞こう！
Impressions, impressions! Let's hear them!
そうだねー
That's right.
えーと、そうですね。印象の変化から言っていきますと...
Well, if I talk about the change in impressions...
まずスバルママ
First, Subaru-mama.
あ、これ奏ちゃんが言うんじゃないの？
Oh, isn't Kanade-chan supposed to say this?
なんで奏ちゃんが言うの、印象を！
Why would Kanade-chan say her own impressions!
そっちか！
Oh, that's what you meant!
あ、あ、え、じゃあ聞きたい聞きたい
Ah, wait, then I want to hear them!
どっちから行こうかなー
Which one should I start with?
目つぶって、こっち！
Eyes closed... this one!
あ、スバちゃんから！
Oh, it's Suba-chan!
もうこっちはスバルだし！
Well, this side is Subaru!
奏は最初は、はい、なんかARKで騒いでるの見て...
At first, Kanade, seeing you making a fuss in ARK...
何だこいつと思って...
...I thought, "Who is this kid?"
何だこいつ！
Who is this kid!
でも、ARKで声が貫通してる頃から...
But ever since your voice was piercing through ARK...
ホロライブの中では、奏は大丈夫だなーっていう...
...I thought, "Among Hololive, Kanade will be okay."
大丈夫だなー！すごい！
"She'll be okay!" Wow!
なんか元気さがあったんですよ。でもね...
There was such energy. But then...
GTAで最後ね、奏ちゃんがね、逮捕された...
...in GTA, in the end, Kanade-chan got arrested...
あの顔やめろお前！近いわ！
Stop making that face! You're too close!
で、なんか逮捕されたりとかね...
And getting arrested and all that...
そのあと奏ちゃん実はね、私もっと頑張りたいです、って...
...after that, Kanade-chan actually called me...
なんか電話してきたりとかね...
...and said, "I want to work harder."
えー！それ言っちゃうの！？あー！恥ずかしい！
Ehh! You're gonna say that!? How embarrassing!
なんかねー、頑張り屋さんなんだなーって思いました。
I thought, "She's really a hard worker."
おめでとう！お誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
さあ、そして次は？次は？
Okay, and next? Next?
じゃあ団長ね。奏ちゃんはね...
It's Danchou's turn. Kanade-chan...
最初デビューした時さ、すごい歌もうまくてね...
...when she first debuted, her singing was so good...
団長とは別の世界の人なんだなーと思って...
...I thought she was from a different world than me...
全然絡めなかったんだけど、でもね、マイクラで...
...so I couldn't talk to her. But in Minecraft...
あのダイヤをね、団長から嘘ついて奪ったりとか...
...you lied and stole those diamonds from Danchou...
そっから、あ、この子はそういう子なんだ、って...
...and I realized, "Oh, she's that kind of kid."
ダイヤ嘘ついて盗むような奴...
The kind of person who lies to steal diamonds...
違うの！
That's not it!
いや、物怖じせずに絡んできてくれたり...
No, you interact without any hesitation...
本当に可愛いの！
...you're really cute!
ノエルママだったら何でも許してくれる...
Noel-mama, you'll forgive anything...
いや許しちゃう！
I'll forgive you!
ダメだろダイヤ勝手に盗むのは！
It's not okay to steal diamonds without permission!
いい子いい子！だから今ではね...
Good girl, good girl! So now...
どんどん後ろ行くのやめて！
Stop moving further and further back!
本当にいい子ですよ。
...she's really a good girl.
そうだねー。いい子だねー。
That's right. She's a good girl.
頑張ってたもんねー！
You've been working hard!
はい、でも本当におめでとうね、お誕生日おめでとう。
Anyway, congratulations! Happy birthday!
来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming!
一緒に歌えて本当に嬉しかったです！
I was so happy to be able to sing together!
スバルたちも嬉しかったぞ！
We were happy too!
いちゃいちゃしやがって！
Look at you two flirting!
さあ、はい, 奏、次、次、次があるからね。
Okay, Kanade, next, next, we have the next part.
めっちゃ台本読むやつ！
The one who's just reading the script!
いや、お前だよ！どこからどう考えても！
No, it's you! No matter how you think about it!
ちゃんと読みます！ちゃんと読んで！
I'll read it properly! Read it properly!
スバルママ、ノエルママ、ありがとうございました！
Subaru-mama, Noel-mama, thank you so much!
奏が生パフォーマンスで一人で頑張るのみて...
Seeing Kanade working hard alone in a live performance...
祝福してもらってもいいですかー！？
...can I get your blessing!?
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! Hooray!
次の曲は！
The next song is...
Beautiful!
Beautiful / 作詞：超哲学 / 作曲：菅谷豊・超哲学
Beautiful / Lyrics: Chotetsugaku / Composition: Yutaka Sugaya, Chotetsugaku
遠くに伸びる影
Shadows stretching far away,
夜の波が消した
were washed away by the night waves.
涙を流したなんて
That I shed tears...
気づかれないまま
...remaining unnoticed.
心を綴るなら
If I were to write out my heart,
傷つく方がマシさ
it would be better to just get hurt.
冷たい風を切って
Cutting through the cold wind,
逃げるように走る
I run as if to escape.
いつかこの雫は
Someday, these drops...
宝石になるのでしょう
...will surely become jewels.
美しい心に
Into a beautiful heart,
生まれ変わる
they will be reborn.
そう信じて
I believe so.
世界で一つだけの
To become the one and only
輝く光になれ
shining light in the world.
私でいい
It's okay to be me,
私を信じて
believing in myself,
ゆくのさ
I will keep going.
空回り
Spinning my wheels...
聞いても まるで
Even if I listen, it's as if...
君道をゆけ
...you should walk your own path.
私でいい
I'm fine as I am.
私の歩幅で
At my own pace.
生きていくのさ
I'll keep on living.
誰かと 比べるのは
Comparing myself with someone else...
避けられない心情
...is an unavoidable feeling.
誰かを 震わすのは
Inspiring someone...
難しい心情
...is a difficult feeling.
無いものを探せば
If I look for what I don't have,
数えきれないけれど
there are countless things.
ゆっくり愛してみよう
But let's try to love slowly,
私という この命を
this life that is me.
世界で一つの
Become the one and only...
輝く光になれ
...shining light in the world.
灯りのない明日を
Even if I face a tomorrow...
迎えたとしても
...with no light.
悲しみの先に
Even if loneliness washes over me...
孤独が押し寄せても
...beyond the sadness.
息をしてる 今日も息をして
I'm breathing, breathing today too,
生きている
I'm living.
世界で一つの
The one and only in the world.
私に幸あれ
May happiness be mine.
涙に幸あれ
May happiness be in my tears.
明日に幸あれ
May happiness be in my tomorrow.
世界で一つの
Become the one and only...
輝く光になれ
...shining light in the world.
泣いてもいい 私を歩いて
It's okay to cry, I'll walk my own path...
いくのさ
...and go on.
涙は頬 流れる
Tears flow down my cheeks...
星のようさ
...like stars.
私になれ 私を叶えて
Become me, fulfill me,
生きていくのさ
I'll keep on living.
いつの日も
Every single day.
はい！ということで
All right! And with that,
いかがでしたでしょうか？
how did you like it?
ちょっとお水だけ飲んできます！
I'm going to go drink some water!
あーー！水うめーーー！
Ahhh! Water tastes great!
はい、それでは えー、この素晴らしき曲の余韻が消えぬ間に
Okay then, while the afterglow of this wonderful song still lingers,
最後の曲 聴いてください。
please listen to the final song.
ハイ！
Here we go!
目を開けて 口ずさむ
Opening my eyes, humming along,
輝ける
shining.
きっと 無敵になる
I'll surely become invincible.
[feel my heart]
[See me become the GREATEST]
[No one can beat me]
[Cuz I'm a GREATEST]
固く結び直した靴紐が
The shoelaces I retied tightly...
羽に見えて
...look like wings to me,
どこまででも跳べる 予感がする
and I have a feeling I can fly anywhere.
追いかけるなんて趣味じゃない
Chasing after isn't my style,
追い越そう明日だって
I'll overtake, even tomorrow.
夢のまんま終わるほど 眠くないわ
I'm not sleepy enough to let it end as just a dream.
何一つかも大丈夫
Everything is alright
奇跡よりも大胆に勝つの
I'll win even more boldly than a miracle
見たことない景色だって
Even scenery I've never seen before
光に満ちていく
Is filling with light
Wanna be the GREATEST
地図ならばこの胸に
If it's a map, it's in this heart
迸る熱がある
There's a surging heat
誰も止めらんない my way
No one can stop my way
Wanna be the GREATEST
弱音も重ねればシンフォニー
Even complaints, if layered, become a symphony
強くなれる歌って
Singing that I can become strong
“きっと無敵になる”
"I'll surely become invincible"
(Feel my light)
部屋で一人描いたステージも
Even the stage I drew alone in my room
覚えていて 居場所になる
I'll remember it, it will be my place
声が聞こえてくる
I can hear voices
深呼吸をして 飛び乗るくらいが正攻法だって
Take a deep breath, jumping in is the standard way
胸を張って踊るのも悪くないわ
It's not bad to dance with your head held high
恐れないで大丈夫
Don't be afraid, it's alright
唱えるたび絶対になるの
Every time I chant, it becomes absolute
一度きりの人生だって
Even in this one-time life
この手で舵を取れ
Take the helm with these hands
Wanna be the GREATEST
私が私として
As myself
輝ける道を行く
I'll go down the shining path
声も煌めいて my day
Even my voice sparkles on my day
Wanna be the GREATEST
目覚めを奏でてオーバーチュア
Play the awakening overture
望むほどに叶って
Granted as much as I wish
もっと素敵になる
I'll become even more wonderful
(Feel my heart)
[Feel my heart]
[See me become the GREATEST]
[No one can beat me]
[Cuz I'm a GREATEST]
Wanna be the GREATEST
諦めた好きの数
The number of things I loved and gave up
上を向く理由がある
There's a reason to look up
涙導いて my beat
Tears guide my beat
Wanna be the GREATEST
傷跡も連れてアレグロ
Take the scars along in allegro
強くなれる歌って
Singing that I can become strong
もっと光指す方へ
Towards where the light shines more
“きっと無敵になる”
"I'll surely become invincible"
(Feel my light)
はい！ということで！
Alright! So!
今聞いていただいたのが、あ、聞いていただいていたのが、もう完全に力がなくなってしまいました。安心して。
What you just heard, ah, what you were hearing—I've completely run out of energy. Rest assured.
今聞いていただいたのが、なんと、奏の初オリ曲！『GREATEST』です！
What you just heard was, would you believe it, Kanade's first original song! 'GREATEST'!
すごい！ジャケットが！
Amazing! Look at the cover art!
作詞・作曲はナナホシ管弦楽団...噛んじゃった。管弦楽団さんです！
The lyrics and music are by Nanahoshi Kangengakudan... I stumbled. It's Nanahoshi Kangengakudan-san!
こちらの楽曲はですね、どういう楽曲か、えー、すごい言うと、簡単に言うと、
Regarding this song, what kind of song is it? Um, if I say it in a big way—or simply put,
韓国から夢を叶えに来た音乃瀬奏なりの、こう、ギラギラソング、キラキラソングみたいな感じとなっています。
It's like a 'sparkling' and 'dazzling' song that reflects Otonose Kanade, who came from Korea to fulfill her dreams.
奏がこういうのを信じてやっていきたいんだみたいなのを伝えて書いていただきました。本当に素敵な楽曲と歌詞、ありがとうございます！めっちゃ気に入ってます！
I told them I wanted to do something I believed in, and they wrote it for me. Thank you so much for the wonderful song and lyrics! I love it so much!
そして、4月21日0時から、この後おそらく3時間、あ、3時間後に楽曲リリースもされます！イエーイ！パチパチ！ありがとう！
And on April 21st at midnight—probably in about 3 hours from now—the song will be released! Yay! *claps* Thank you!
最高すぎたわ、ありがとう。MVはね、ちょっと後日公開なんですけれども、ぜひ公開されたらいっぱい見てください！
It was just the best, thank you. The MV will be released at a later date, but please watch it a lot when it's out!
はい、新曲の披露もできたところで、告知タイムです！
Alright, now that I've performed the new song, it's time for announcements!
まず1つ目は、皆さんお待ちかね、グッズの紹介です！
First up is what you've all been waiting for: the merchandise reveal!
こちら！音乃瀬奏誕生日記念2025！フルセットはこんな感じになってます！かわいい！
Here it is! Otonose Kanade Birthday Commemoration 2025! This is the full set! It's so cute!
かわいいだろ？かわいいだろ？今回のキービジュアルは、胡麻ママに描いていただきました！かわいいでしょ！
Isn't it cute? Isn't it cute? This time's key visual was drawn by Goma-mama! It's cute, right!
なで、でもオリ曲はね、みんなすごい『念願のオリ曲！』みたいな感じだったから
But everyone was like, 'The long-awaited original song!'
いっぱい喜んでもらえて嬉しいです！
I'm so glad everyone was so happy about it!
それではグッズ、ひとつずつ見ていきましょう！
So let's take a look at the merchandise one by one!
ひとつめ！
Number one!
ワイドラバーマット！
Wide rubber mat!
キービジュアルの、オリジナルパジャマを着た奏での、きゅあ！なデザインのラバーマットです！
A rubber mat with a 'Kyua!' design of Kanade in original pajamas from the key visual!
キーボードとマウスを乗せて使えるワイドサイズになっています！
It's a wide size that you can use with your keyboard and mouse!
ふたつめはこちら！
Number two is this!
奏が落書きしちゃったｗ Tシャツです！
The 'Kanade scribbled on it lol' T-shirt!
あのー、実際に奏がね、描き下ろしデザインの、Tシャツです！書きました！
Um, this is a T-shirt with a design actually drawn by Kanade! I wrote it!
よかったら奏と一緒にTシャツ1枚持ってる民になってくれませんか？
Would you like to become one of the people who own a T-shirt just like Kanade's?
いっぱい買ってください！
Please buy lots of them!
続いてみっつめ！
Next is number three!
タンブラーです！
The tumbler!
衣装のね、こちらの、リボンをモチーフにした、日常使いができる落ち着いたデザイン！
It has a calm design for daily use, with a motif of the ribbon on my outfit!
会社などで、使って、ぜひとも奏を宣伝してください！
Please use it at your office or elsewhere to promote Kanade!
そして、次はこちら！
And next is this!
奏のぷにぷにクッション！
Kanade's Squishy Cushion!
ま、いっか.寝ている表情のフェイスクッションです！
Well, whatever. It's a face cushion with a sleeping expression!
特別に、奏のほっぺを、ぷにぷに、してよしと台本に書かれていますが、
It says in the script that it's okay to squish Kanade's cheeks, but...
許可した覚えは、ありません！
I don't remember giving permission for that!
ぷにぷにじゃないからなー！はい！
It's not squishy! Okay!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the bonus for purchasing the full set!
奏の直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
A postcard with Kanade's handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
今回、数量限定ではないので、フルセット買ってくれた方全員に直筆サインが届きます！
This time it's not limited, so everyone who buys the full set will get a signature!
みんな、安心してね。戦争じゃないから、ゆっくり買ってもいいんだぞ！
Everyone, don't worry. It's not a war, so you can take your time!
奏は腱鞘炎になりながら書くからね！頑張って書くぞー！
Kanade will write them until I get tendonitis! I'll do my best!
今回は、誕生日記念2025お礼ボイスも付きます！
This time, it also comes with a Birthday Celebration 2025 Thank-You Voice!
さらに、フルセット特典として、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付きます！
Plus, you'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game as a bonus!
カードは、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります！
The card is only for those who purchase from the Hololive Official Shop!
すごーい！かわいい！
Amazing! So cute!
特典につくのは、推しアピールできる推しメンカードです！
The bonus card is an 'Oshimen' card to show off your favorite member!
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページにてご確認ください！
Please check the website for card details and how to play!
カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください！以上、グッズ紹介でした！
Note that cards are only in Japanese! That's all for the merchandise!
そして、告知ふたつめはこちら！
And here is the second announcement!
なんと、LINEスタンプ制作決定！！すごーい！
Believe it or not, we're making LINE stamps!! Amazing!
可愛いでしょ？すまそーって、すまそーってやってるスタンプ、パチパチ、ありがとう！
Aren't they cute? The 'Sory-ish' stamp, yay, thank you!
えーっと、発売日はまだ未定ですが、こんな感じの可愛いイラストのスタンプです！
The release date is still TBD, but the stamps will have cute illustrations!
セリフとかもね、奏が考えて作ってもらっているので、乞うご期待！
I'm also coming up with the lines myself, so look forward to it!
詳細は、後日また告知をします！お楽しみに！以上、告知でした！
I'll announce more details later! Stay tuned! That's all!
ということで、奏生誕祭2025、あ、違う。こっちだ。
So, Kanade Birthday Celebration 2025... oh, wait. This one.
毎回間違える。2025、はい、いかがでしたでしょうか？
I get it wrong every time. 2025, yes, how did you like it?
初めてのね、アコギの挑戦だったり、すごい『かっこいい！』ってコメントしてくれてたの見たよ！
My first challenge with an acoustic guitar... I saw your comments saying 'So cool!'
嬉しかったし、すごい頑張って準備したので、いっぱい見ていただけて嬉しい限りです！
I'm so glad so many of you watched, since I worked so hard on the preparations!
本当に嬉しいよ！オリ曲も公開できて！
I'm really happy! I was also able to release my original song!
あの、リリースされたらいっぱい聴いてね！
Please listen to it a lot when it's released!
すごい、まだコメント欄がぷにぷにの下りになってるｗ
Wow, the comments section is still on the 'squishy' thing lol
おせーんだよ。予測して打て！
You're too slow. Type in advance!
拾えねーだろ！えー、ということで、えー、
I won't be able to pick it up! Well, so, um...
この後のスケジュールをちょっとざっくり皆様にお教えしますと、
Let me give you a quick overview of the schedule after this...
21時10分からグッズ販売開始を行います！
Merchandise sales will start at 21:10!
そして、21時20分から、あ、こちら.20分から、メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもありますので、そちらもよろしくお願いします！
And from 21:20... members-only encore live! Please check that out too!
今がメン限入り時だよ、みんな！今、今、今入りな！
Now is the best time to join the membership! Join now, now, now!
はい、そして、たぶんもう終わりかな？忘れてないよね？
Yes, and I think that's about it? I haven't forgotten anything, right?
はい、ということで、じゃあ.お疲れ様でしたー！来てくれてありがとうー！イエーイ！
Okay then... thank you for your hard work! Thanks for coming! Yay!
あ、待って待って待って！待って待って待って！
Oh, wait wait wait! Wait wait wait!
一個大事なの忘れてた！
I forgot one important thing!
一番大事なお知らせ！はい、告知！
The most important announcement! Yes, an announcement!
それでは、皆様聞いてください。奏からのもうオリ曲並みに大事なお知らせ！
Everyone, please listen. An announcement just as important as the original song!
タラーン！あしたは月曜日！！
Ta-da! Tomorrow is Monday!!
げ、げつようび、げつようび。ルルル...
Mon, Monday, Monday. Lu lu lu...
みんな、夢から覚める時間だよー。
Everyone, it's time to wake up from the dream.
もう夢から覚める時間だよー。
It's time to wake up from the dream.
奏の生誕ライブ、アンコールライブが終わったらもう終わりなんだよ.えーい。
Once Kanade's birthday live and encore live are over, it's all over. There.
あした学校だね.会社だね.えーい。
School tomorrow, huh? Office tomorrow, huh? There.
見てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for watching!
やっと夢に向けて一歩踏み出せました！！
I've finally taken a step toward my dream!!
私はもっともっと輝きたい！！
I want to shine more and more!!
もっと素敵な景色を見せられるように
So that I can show you even more wonderful sights
がんばります！何卒！
I will do my best! Please support me!